A Guide to the Blackford Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #38-204
Blackford Family Papers 1849-1870
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
38-204
ca. 150 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift 1935
Container List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence of the Henson Family., 1859, 1864 (Box Box 1)
  - Correspondence of Staige Davis Blackford, U.S.A. Ambulance Corp., 1917 (Box Box 1)
  - Correspondence of the Blackford Family., 1917-1932 (Box Box 1)
  - Correspondence of Launcelot Minor Blackford, 3rd Battalion, 53rd Infantry., 1919 (Box Box 1)
  - Letters and Sermons from Ambler M. Blackford to his mother., 1921-1932 (Box Box 1)
- Educational Papers of Launcelot Minor Blackford
  - Abstracts of Lectures submitted by Launcelot Minor Blackford at the University of Virginia., 1857 (Box Box 1)
  - Algebra Exercises by Launcelot Minor Blackford., 1849 (Box Box 1)
  - Announcements and Invitations sent to Launcelot Minor Blackford., 1855-1867 (Box Box 1)
  - Compositions and Essays by Launcelot Minor Blackford., 1850 (Box Box 1)
  - Copies of the Monthly Reports of Scholarships used by Launcelot Minor Blackford while teaching at " Macon, " Powhatan County., 1854-1855 (Box Box 1)
  - Course of Instructions for Educational Institutions., 1857, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Foreign Language Examinations taken by Launcelot Minor Blackford at Albemarle Military Institute, Charlottesville., 1857-1858 (Box Box 1)
  - Foreign Language Exercises by Launcelot Minor Blackford at Wood Academy, Lynchburg., 1851-1855 (Box Box 1)
  - Foreign Language Translations by Launcelot Minor Blackford at Wood Academy, Lynchburg., 1851-1853 (Box Box 1)
  - Foreign Language Translations by Launcelot Minor Blackford at Wood Academy, Lynchburg., 1854-1855 (Box Box 1)
  - Marking Books used by Launcelot Minor Blackford while teaching at " Macon, " Powhatan County., 1854 (Box Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Educational Papers of Launcelot Minor Blackford., 1851 (Box Box 1)
  - Papers of Launcelot Minor Blackford re Debates of the Literary Prose Debate Society, Jefferson Society, and Washington Society., 1852-1857 (Box Box 1)
- Educational Papers of the Blackford Family
  - "An Object Lesson in Hygiene," an address delivered by Charles Minor Blackford., 1901 (Box Box 1)
  - Notes on Contracts., 1917 (Box Box 1)
  - Notes on Miscellaneous Courses kept by L. Dabney Overton., ca. 1930 (Box Box 2)
  - Notes on Embryology Course kept by Launcelot Minor Blackford, Jr., 1919-1920 (Box Box 2)
  - Notes on Literary Courses kept by Launcelot Minor Blackford, Jr., ca. 1920 (Box Box 2)
  - Notes on Organic Chemistry Course kept by Ambler M. Blackford., 1910 (Box Box 2)
  - Notes on Organic Chemistry Course kept by Ambler M. Blackford., 1911 (Box Box 2)
  - Notes on Psychology Course kept by James J. Chapman., ca. 1930 (Box Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Advertisement for Cyrus M. Berry Pianos and Organs., 1920 (Box Box 2)
  - Drawings for the Virginia Reel by Launcelot Minor Blackford, Jr., and Miscellanous Papers., 1920 (Box Box 2)
  - Military Papers--notes on training and orders--of Launcelot Minor Blackford, Jr., 1918-1919 (Box Box 2)
  - Photographs of Various Unidentified People., n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Reminiscences of the Funerals of Judge Claggett B. Jones and Dr. Edwin Anderson Alderman., 1931 (Box Box 2)